# **MEGAN GILPIN**

New York, New York 10031 T: (620) 481-1538 E: megangilpin@gmail.com

Linkedln: linkedin.com/in/megan-gilpin Github: github.com/megangilpin Portfolio: megangilpin.com

## **SUMMARY**

Full stack engineer at the intersection of functionality and design with 10 years of design experience developing creative consumer-focused products. Highly skilled communicator and project manager who works well in fast-paced environments with tight deadlines.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo-Client, Prisma, Jest.js, Enzyme.js, Material UI

APPLICATIONS: Git, Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Word, Excel, PowerPoint

# **PROJECTS**

#### **CHEF'S MENU**

React, Material UI, Mongo DB Github: github.com/megangilpin/chefs-menu

Full stack online market place for home-cooked meals created by a professional chef.

- Spearheaded user flow and component re-usability through conditional rendering on Chef's profile page
- Utilized React Hooks to create a user context for logged in users and a shopping cart context using local storage
- Created database model for messaging and all routes/controllers for sending and fetching messages.

#### **ARRYVL**

React, Bootstrap, Mongo DB Gi

Github: github.com/megangilpin/finito

Full stack app that tracks the user's journey to their destination and notifies a friend once they have arrived.

- Developed initial prototype in Adobe XD along with all design assets and logo
- Integrated Google Maps API to handle geolocation of destination and calculation of trip time based on transit mode
- Built reusable and responsive sidebar and map display components with the help of Bootstrap Containers and Grids

# **SHOPAHOLIC**

React, Apollo-Client, GraphQL, Prisma Github: github.com/megangilpin/shopaholic

Full stack peer to peer clothing store with user authentication and credit card checkout.

- Created dynamic UI with CSS transitions to keep users focus on products
- Implemented GraphQL server with auto generated queries through Prisma and custom resolvers with GraphQL-Yoga
  PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **ORIGINAL PENGUIN**

Designer

NY, NY 2014 - 2020

- Oversaw concept, design, and production of the global assortment; 450 skus per year in over 30 countries.
- Drove improvements in design processes and sourcing operations to improve margin by 10% within the first year, consecutively achieved new maximum target margin per sku in all following years.
- Lead large scale category relaunch from development to production, resulting in 83% growth in bottoms share of the total sales mix.

# **KENNETH COLE**

Associate Designer NY, NY 2014

Assistant Designer NY, NY 2009 – 2014

- Partnered with cross-functional teams to interpret selling results, sku plans, and design calendar to create product within given price ranges and time frames.
- Managed CAD designer to ensure optimal productivity.
- Communicated with overseas agents in over 5 countries through all stages of development and production.

#### **EDUCATION**

## FULL STACK BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE / COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY - 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in full stack web development.

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS / ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF ART - CHICAGO